## AKHIL PATEL



+91 - 908 574 0500 contact.akhilpatel@gmail.com www.akhilpatel.xyz I believe in creating effective and engaging experiences for the masses by a seamless integration of technology (artificial intelligence, to be specific, in tech domain) and user-centered design, to create next-gen solutions.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### **Busigence Technologies**

Design Associate
Dec 2016 - Jan 2017 (6 weeks)
Gurgaon, India

#### **Robert Bosch UX Studio**

Experience Design Intern May 2016 - July 2016 (8 weeks) Bangalore, India

## Usability and HCI Lab, IIT-G

HCI Intern

Dec 2015 - Jan 2016 (5 weeks) Guwahati, India

- Applied Design Thinking and Shneiderman's heuristics to create the overall experience of the cognitive computing based data science product.
- Collaborated with full stack developers, data engineers and data scientists in product development to keep a track on technical constraints in design.
- Designed and prototyped an induction kit for the new joining Bosch employees to communicate Bosch values by redefining the Identity.
- Identified user needs with the help of user-centered design research.
- Conceptualized Bosch Employment Portal and 'My HR' mobile app.
- Learned the basics of Augmented Reality and applied it in the domain of smart learning solutions for college students in Electronics Lab.
- · Conducted user studies through questionnaires, surveys and interviews.
- Prototyped an AR mobile app in Unity3D for user testing and evaluation.

#### EDUCATION

# Indian Institute of Technology - Guwahati | 2014 - 2018 (expected)

Bachelors of Design | CPI: 8.29 Interaction Design and HCI

#### SKILLS & TOOLS

### Design & Research:

- Design Thinking
- · Contextual Enquiry/User Research
- Information Architecture
- Rapid Prototyping
- Heuristic Evaluation
- UI/Visual Design
- User Testing

#### **Design Tools:**

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Sketch

#### **Prototyping Tools:**

- Axure
- InVision
- Unity3D

## Development:

- Bootstrap
- Angular JS\*

\*Elementary proficiency

#### PROJECTS

#### **DRIVERSITY | Valeo Innovation Challenge 2016**

Jan 2016

#### Keywords: Interaction Design, Augmented Reality, Automobile

- Conceptualized and proposed an Augmented Reality based multimodal system to make the car of 2030 more intelligent, intuitive and fun.
- Created an AR based prototype using Google Cardboard to test the concept.
- Shortlisted as World Semifinalist (top 24) out of 1300+ teams worldwide.

#### TUNO | Honeywell AeroChallenge 2016

Dec 2015

## Keywords: App Design, IoT, Aircraft Maintenance

- Designed an application to facilitate the collaboration of aircraft staff in the aircraft maintenance process to reduce the overall turnaround time.
- Received an **Honourable Mention** for the proposed mobile application.

#### **FACEMATCH | Experience Design to Match Faces with Names** Oct 2016

Keywords: User Experience, Research, Interaction Design, Education

- Adopted a data-driven approach to design an experience for Teachers/ Professors to easily remember names of students every new semester.
- Focused on progressive accuracy improvement and quality data collection during the process flow to enhance the customized education experience.

## **ICT based Training Modules for Health Workers**

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016

Keywords: User Research, HCI, Training, Rural Health

- Conducted extensive rural field research and user contextual enquiry.
- Designed interactive training and learning modules for Rural Community Health Workers supported through mobile phone based interactions.